38 chapter 39 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 39 CD
Sam I should say that for a cab horse I was very well off in indeed; my driver
was my owner, and it was his interest to treat me well and to not overwork me,
even had he not been in so good a man as
he was; but there were a great many horses which belonged to the large cab
owners who let them out to their drivers for so much money a day. As the horses
did not belong to these men the only thing they thought of was how to get
their money out of them, first, to pay the master, and then to provide for their own
living; and a dreadful time some of these horses had of it.
Of course, I understood but little, but it was often talked over on the stand, and
the governor, who was a kind hearted man and fond of horses, would sometimes speak
up if one came in very much jaded or illed One day shabby miserable looking
driver, who went by the name of Sidi Sam”, brought in his horse looking dreadfully
beat, and the governor said: “You and your horse look more fit for the police
station than for this rank.” The man flung his tattered rug over the
horse, turned full round upon the Governor and said in a voice that sounded almost
desperate: “If the police have any business with the matter it ought to be
with the masters who charge us so much, or with Affairs that are fixed so low. If
a man has to pay 18 shillings a day for
the use of a cab and two horses, as many
of us have to do in the season, and must
make that up before we earn a penny for ourselves I say it is more than hard
work; nine shillings a day to get out of each horse before you begin to get your
own living. You know that's true, and if the horses don't work we must starve, and
I and my children have known what that is before now. I've six of them and only
one earns anything I'm on the stand 14 or 16 hours a day, and I haven't had a
Sunday these 10 or 12 weeks; you know Skinner never gives a day if he can help
it, and if I don't work hard, tell me who does! I want a warm coat and the
Macintosh but with so many to feed how can a man get it? I had to pledge my
clock a week ago to pay Skinner, and I shall never see it
again.” Some of the other drivers stood round nodding their heads and saying he
was right. The man went on: “You that have your own horses and cabs, or drive for
good masters, have a chance of getting on and a chance of doing right; I haven't. We
can't charge more than six p a mile after the first, within the 4 mile radius.
This very morning I had to go a clear six miles and only took three shillings.
I could not get a return fair and had to come all the way back; there's 12 miles
for the horse and three shillings for me.
After that I had a three mile fair and there were bags and boxes enough to have
brought in a good many two pences if they had been put outside; but you know
how people do; all that could be piled up inside on the front seat were put in and
three heavy boxes went on the top. That was 6 and the fair one and six then I
got a return for a shilling.
Now that makes 18 miles for the horse and six shillings for me; there's three
shillings still for that horse to earn and nine shillings for the afternoon
horse before I touch a penny. Of course, it is not always so bad as that, but you
know it often is, and I say it is a
mockery to tell a man that he must not overwork his horse, for when a beast is
downright tired there's nothing but the whip that will keep his legs are going
you can't help yourself— —you must put your wife and children before the horse;
the masters must look to that, we can't. I don't ill use my horse for the sake of
it; none of you can say I do. There's wrong lays somewhere— —never a day's rest,
never a quiet hour with a wife and children. I often feel like an old man,
though I'm only 45 You know how quick some of the gentry
are to suspect us of cheating and overcharging; why, they stand with their
purses in their hands counting it over to a penny and looking at us as if we were
pickpockets. I wish some of them had to
sit on my box 16 hours a day and get a living out of it and 18 shillings
besides and that in all weathers; they would not be so uncommon particular
never to give us a six p over or to cram all the luggage
inside. Of course, some of them tip us pretty handsome now and then, or else we
could not live; but you can't depend upon that.” The men who stood round much
approved the speech, and one of them said, “It is desperate hard, and if a man
sometimes does what is wrong it is no wonder,
and if he gets a dram too much who's to blow him
up?” Jerry had taken no part in this conversation, but I never saw his face look so sad
before. The governor had stood with both his hands in his pockets; now he took his
handkerchief out of his hat and wiped his forehead. “You've beaten me, Sam,” he said,
“for all it's true, and I won't cast it up to you anymore about the police; it was
the look in that horse's eye that came over me. It is hard lines for man and it
is hard lines for beast, and who's to mend it I don't know: but anyway you
might tell the poor beast that you were sorry to take it out of him in that way.
Sometimes a kind word is all we can give him poor brutes, and is wonderful what they do
understand.” A few mornings after this talk a new man came on the stand with Sam's
cab hello said one, “what's up with cidd Sam?” “He's ill in bed,” said the man; “he was
taken last night in the yard, and could scarcely crawl home. His wife sent a boy
this morning to say his father was in a high fever and could not get out, so I'm
here instead.” The next morning the same man came again. “How is Sam?” inquired the
governor. “He's gone,” said the man. “What, gone? You don't mean to say he's
dead?” “Just snuffed out,” said the other; “he died at 4:00 this morning; all yesterday
he was raving— —raving about SK and having no Sundays. 'I never had a Sunday's rest
those were his last words.” No one spoke for a while, and then
the governor said, “I'll tell you what, mates, this is a warning for
us end of chapter